Guide to the Margaret Croyden Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Margaret Croyden papers
1965-2011
YCAL MSS 577
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
21.77
(39 boxes) + 1 broadside
The Margaret Croyden papers contain writings, research material, photographs, audiovisual material, and personal papers. Writings include drafts, printed versions, and photocopies of printed versions of reviews and essays on theater-related topics as well as corrected drafts of her fourth book, The Years in Between (Xlibris, 2011). Video recordings appear to date chiefly from Croyden's tenure with the CBS TV series Camera Three during the 1970s. There are audio recordings and other materials relating to theater director Peter Brook and possibly to Croyden's Conversations with Peter Brook: 1970-2000 (Theatre Communications Group, 2003). Other materials in the collection include clippings, computer disks, correspondence, photographs, a laptop, and slides.
Croyden, Margaret, 1922-2015
Camera Three Productions
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Locus Solus Rare Books on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 2005. Additional material received in 2011. Gift of Ron Melk and Phyliss Dain, 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 12, 17, 34, and 36 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 6-11, 16, 35, 38 and 39 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 37: Restricted until 2066. For further information consult appropriate curator.
Margaret Croyden
Margaret Croyden, American theater critic and journalist and host of the television program Camera Three. In addition to shorter works on the theater, her major publications include Lunatics, Lovers, & Poets: The Contemporary Experimental Theatre (1974), the memoir In the Shadow of the Flame: Three Journeys (1993), Conversations with Peter Brook: 1970-2000 (2003), and The Years In Between: A Reporter's Journey World War II--The Cold War (2011).
Biographical information taken from "Margaret Croyden." Contemporary Authors Online. Detroit: Gale, 2004. Gale Biography In Context. Web. 29 Feb. 2012.
Scope and Contents
The Margaret Croyden papers contain writings, research material, photographs, audiovisual material, and personal papers. Writings contain drafts and printed versions and photocopies (of printed versions) of reviews and essays on theater related topics as well as corrected drafts of her fourth book, The Years in between (2011). Video appears to date chiefly to Croyden's tenure with the CBS TV series Camera Three during the 1970s. There are audio recordings and other materials relating to Peter Brook, possibly to Croyden's Conversations with Peter Brook: 1970-2000 (2003). Other materials in the collection include clippings, computer disks, correspondence, photographs, a laptop, and slides.
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: November 2005 Acquisition, 2011 Addition to November 2005 Acquisition, and December 2015 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time. Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, correspondence and writings can be found in all three groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Researchers should also note that similar material can be arranged differently in each acquisition, depending on how the material was organized when it was received by the library.
Camera three (Television program); American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Critics -- United States; Journalists -- United States; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Electronic documents; Photographic prints; Scrapbooks; Sound recordings; Video recordings; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Critics -- United States -- 20th Century; Journalists -- United States -- 20th Century; Brook, Peter, 1925-; Croyden, Margaret, 1922-2015; Grotowski, Jerzy, 1933-1999; Camera Three Productions
- November 2005 Acquisition, 1965-2005; 8.75; (11 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Material arranged as received by the library.
  Scope and Contents
  Folder headings listed below are transcribed (quotation marks) or supplied. Dates given below are largely circa dates.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Locus Solus Rare Books on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 2005.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 6-10 contain audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be available upon request. Contact Access Services for further information.
  - Miscellaneous writings, undated; (5 computer disks) (Box 1)
    Computer disks are restricted. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services.
    20051110-c.0001: Tempest2, Tempest, 93 piece...
    20051110-c.0002: Peter Brook Interview
    20051110-c.0003: Brook Manuscript 2002
    20051110-c.0004: Conversations with Peter Brook Complete Mss
    20051110-c.0005: Farrar Straus Conversations with Peter Brook
  - Material relating to Peter Brook, [circa 1970-1990]; 2 (Box 1)
  - "Letters - Shadows of the Flame", 1993-1994, undated (Box 1)
  - American Theatre volume 22 number 4, 2005 April (Box 1)
  - "'Letter From Paris' Theatre Week Jan. 21, 1991", 1991 January 21 (Box 1)
  - The Winter of Our Desire, draft, computer printout, undated (Box 1)
  - "'Articulating Madness,' Peter Brook's L'Homme qui and Pelias", 1993 June 28 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous writings, 1991-1993, undated; 2 (Box 1)
  - "Dream", [circa 1965-1975] (Box 1)
  - "Taormina", 1989 (Box 1)
  - "Orgast - Brook, Oct. 3, 1971" (Box 1)
  - Reviews of "The Mahabhar", 1985 (Box 1)
  - "The Man Who...", 1993 (Box 1)
  - "Brook Biography", 1992, undated (Box 1)
  - "Antony & Cleo", 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - "General Characteristics, Questions & Answers", undated (Box 1)
  - "Village Voice, Peter Brook's 'Tempest' Feb. 12, 1991", 1990, undated (Box 1)
  - "Peter Brooks: Carmen 1983" (Box 1)
  - "Tempest," draft, computer printout, 1990 December (Box 1)
  - "Man Who Reviews + Miscellaneous", 1994-1995, undated (Box 1)
  - "The Center", 1977-1982, undated (Box 1)
  - "All Mahabharata", 1970-1986, undated (Box 1)
  - "Brook Marat God", 1965-1970, undated (Box 1)
  - "Peter Brook's Oedipus", 1968, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous writings on Peter Brook, undated; 3 (Box 2)
  - "Peter Brook 2004 Tierno Bokar", 2004-2005, undated (Box 2)
  - "Correspondence re: 'Conversations with Peter Brook'", 2001 (Box 2)
  - "Coversations - Brook - 2003 - P. R. Reviews", 2003, undated (Box 2)
  - "Miscellaneous articles by Margaret Croyden", 1990-2000, undated (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 1986, undated (Box 2)
  - Material relating to Peter Brook, 2002, undated (Box 2)
  - "Midsummer Dream (Brook) Jan. 17, 1991", 1970-1971, undated (Box 2)
  - Material relating to Mahabharata, 1987, undated; 4 (Box 2)
  - "Meetings With Remarkable Men", 1979 (Box 2)
  - "Brook - New York", 1980 (Box 2)
  - "After Africa", 1973 (Box 2)
  - "The Mahabharata", 1985-1987, undated (Box 2)
  - "Dream file NY Times", 1971 (Box 2)
  - "Brook's US Cherry Orchard Miscellaneous", 1968 (Box 2)
  - Printed ephemera, 2001, undated (Box 2)
  - "Shadow of the Flame reviews and PR", 1993-1994, undated (Box 3)
  - "Theatre Week Bobby Lewis", 1990 February 19 (Box 3)
  - "Amos Oz," draft, computer printout, undated (Box 3)
  - "PR Brook", 2003-2004, undated (Box 3)
  - "Clippings/Publicity - Margaret Croyden", 1974-2004 (Box 3)
  - "Autobiography - Margaret Croyden", 1977-2005, undated (Box 3)
  - "Brook Agents", 1984-1993 (Box 3)
  - "Personal Correspondence + Fan Mail", 1973-1984 (Box 3)
  - "Miscellaneous Articles & Reviews by Margaret Croyden", 1968-2001, undated (Box 3)
  - "The International Theater Conference in Turkey", 1991 July 22 (Box 3)
  - "David Rabe", 1991 (Box 3)
  - "Tony Randall etc., Theater Week Dec. 9, 1991", 1991 December 9 (Box 3)
  - "Theater Week...", 1989-1990; 2 (Box 3)
  - "Bill Irwin & Sam Beckett", 1992 November (Box 3)
  - "Juan & Reyes", 1992 (Box 3)
  - "American Theatre Sept 1992 Grotowski: The Experiment Continues", 1992 September (Box 3)
  - "Critics vs Critics", 1992 July 6 (Box 3)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 3)
  - "Vogue Dec 1975 Cuslak & the Woods", 1975 December (Box 3)
  - "A Voyage With Philip Glass and David Henry Hwang", 1992 October 19 (Box 3)
  - "The Weisslers of B'way Dec 6 1993", 1993 December (Box 3)
  - "Andre Serban: 'A Director Revolt,' Feb 21 '94 Theater Week", 1994 February 21 (Box 3)
  - "Intimate Vanya - Andre Gregory", 1994 November 6 (Box 3)
  - "Harvey Lichtenstein", 1994 September 25 (Box 3)
  - "Letter From Israel - Cameri", 1994 August (Box 3)
  - "Israel 1997/Womens Conf.", 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - "Italy 1999", 1999-2001, undated (Box 3)
  - "Blair's World", 1995 (Box 3)
  - "Report From L.A.", 1995 July 24 (Box 3)
  - "Asian Cultural Council", 1975-1987, undated (Box 3)
  - "Egypt '96", 1996 (Box 3)
  - Denver Center Theatre Company material, 2000, undated (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - "London 1994-5", 1986-1995 (Box 4)
  - "Lectures", 1970-1977 (Box 4)
  - "Paris", 1988-1993, undated (Box 4)
  - "Robert Lepage 1999..." (Box 4)
  - "Personal File Correspondence etc.", 1973-2000, undated (Box 4)
  - "Letter From Chicago", 1994 July 10 (Box 4)
  - "Unpublished Pieces", undated (Box 4)
  - "Shakespeare Lecture", 1998 (Box 4)
  - "Shadow: Promotion + PR", 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - "Flame: (Film People), etc.", 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - "Shadow Flame", 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - "Asia Notes", 1998 (Box 4)
  - "Shiraz Festival General Iran", 1971 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous writings, 1969-1990, undated; 2 (Box 4)
  - "The Tempest", undated (Box 4)
  - "Theater Week July 16, 1990 TCG Piece", 1990 July 16 (Box 4)
  - "Voznesensky 1/29/90 Theater Week", 1990 January 29 (Box 4)
  - "Brook's King Lear", 1971, undated (Box 4)
  - American Theatre issues, 2001, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, 1998-2000 (Box 4)
  - "Vienna 2000", [circa 2000] (Box 4)
  - "Lunatics, Lovers and Poets Reviews", 1974, undated (Box 4)
  - "Pelleas", 1992-1993 (Box 4)
  - Photographs, 1969, undated; 2 (Box 5)
  - "Israeli Contacts", 1994-2000 (Box 5)
  - Calendars, 1984-1986; 3 (Box 5)
  - Notebooks, 1970-2001, undated; 11 (Box 5)
  - "Notes on Brook [?] Out", undated (Box 5)
  - "PW Review...", 2003 (Box 5)
  - "Early Pieces on Peter Brook...", 1985, undated (Box 5)
  - "Grotowski", 1977-2001, undated; 3 (Box 5)
  - Camera Three Presents "The Body Speaks" Part I [The Plastiques] 30 minutes, WCBS-TV, undated; YCALMSS577_0001; 1; 00:29:24 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102301570)
    Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be available upon request. Contact Access Services for further information.
  - Camera Three Presents "The Body Speaks'" Part II [The Corporals], WCBS-TV, undated; YCALMSS577_0002; 1; 00:28:25 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102301588)
  - Camera Three, "The Living Theatre" Part II Camera 3 B, 1976 April 7; YCALMSS577_0003; 1; 00:29:37 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102301596)
  - "Camera Three, 49-69 Jerzey Grotowski Pt 2...", undated; YCALMSS577_0004; 1; 00:30:26 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102301604)
  - "Camera Three, 'Why Alice?'" Part I, 1975 February 7; YCALMSS577_0005; 1; 00:29:51 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102301612)
  - "Camera Three, 'Why Alice?'" Part II, 1975 February 7; YCALMSS577_0006; 1; 00:29:44 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102301620)
  - "Camera Three, 'The Magic of Peter Brooks pt. 1'", 1975 February 14; YCALMSS577_0007; 1; 00:31:57 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002102301638)
  - "Camera Three 'Terminal'", 1976 April 7; YCALMSS577_0008; 1; 00:29:40 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002102301646)
  - "Camera Three '3 The Greek Plays'" Pt. 1 Medea/Electra", undated; YCALMSS577_0009; 1; 00:30:09 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002102301653)
  - "Camera Three '3 The Greek Plays'" Pt. 2 The Trojan Women", YCALMSS577_0010; 1; 00:30:10 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002102301661)
  - "Open Theater 'Terminal' The Living Theatre, 'The Plague,' 'Why Alice?' Part 1 [and unidentified title], undated; YCALMSS577_0011; 1; 01:57:47 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002102301679)
  - "Inside Broadway / Margaret Croyden", 1994 February 2; YCALMSS577_0012; 1; 00:29:43 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002102301687)
    A letter, dated 1994-04-04, included with the tape reads: Dear Ms. Croyden [It] was pleasure meeting you again. We were delighted by your performance on our show. It was very interesting hearing about your family, your life and your adventures. You must come back again to talk about your New York experiences with the "avant garde". All the best, Susan Haskins, Inside Broadway
  - "Arena Stage, London Weekend TV, 'Crime and Punishment' Yuri Lyubimov", 1986 October 15; YCALMSS577_0013; 1; 00:49:20; The tape ends abruptly. A note included with the tape says it was damaged. NTSC (Box 7, Item barcode 39002102301695)
  - "P. Brook - Nat'l Press Club", 1992 March 8; YCALMSS577_0014; 1; 00:26:33 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002102301703)
  - "Joe Papp, 3 Greek Plays, Part 1 and 2", undated; YCALMSS577_0015; 1; 01:53:46 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002102301711)
  - "Cieslak Part I, Part II; Grotowski Part II; Peter Brook: 'Tempest' Part I", undated; YCALMSS577_0016; 1; 00:31:06 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002102301729)
  - "Gesher Theatre 'Adam Resurrected' by Alex Chevinsky, after the novel by Yoram Kaniuk directed by Arye, the world premiere Vienna 1993, the Israeli premiere Tel Aviv 1993 October (Hebrew), YCALMSS577_0017; 1; 00:21:40 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002102301737)
  - "Irene Worth - Actress, Elizabeth [Swoos?] and Her Music Pt II Only", undated; YCALMSS577_0018; 1; 00:57:49 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002102301745)
  - "Camera Three 'Irene Worth: Actress'", undated; YCALMSS577_0019; 1; 00:51:55 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002102301752)
  - "Approaches to Acting, Part 1: Lee Strasberg, Part 2: Andrew Gregory, Part 3: 'Real Reel'", undated; YCALMSS577_0020; 1; 01:31:08 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002102301760)
  - "Camera Three - 'Andrei Serban'", undated; YCALMSS577_0021; 1; 00:33:31 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002102301778)
  - "Camera Three - Yale Drama - Part 1 + Part 2, Sylvia Plath - Getting There", undated; YCALMSS577_0022; 1; 01:32:26 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002102301786)
  - "Columbia Lecture" (audiotape reel), 1970 January 15; 1 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002104888640)
  - Audiocassettes, undated
    - "Peter Brook - copy, film "Sacred Dances", 1971 July 19; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888442)
    - "1K BBC / 2K BBC - copy", undated; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888459)
    - "Brook MAHA", undated; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888467)
    - "Brook 3, 4, 5", undated; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888475)
    - "Peter Brook - copy, London Film", 1977; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888483)
    - "Peter Brook, Stratford", 1978 August 14; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888491)
    - "P. Brook interview on NPR in Washington", 1992 March 10; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888509)
    - "Peter Brook - copy", 1971 August 30; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888517)
    - "Peter Brook - original", 1971 August 30; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888525)
    - "1K BBC / 2K BBC - original", undated; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888533)
    - "Brook - 3 - OK", undated; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888541)
    - "Argast 2 - Original", undated; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888558)
    - "Peter Brook - copy, film "Sacred Dances"', 1971 July 19; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888566)
    - "Peter Brook", 1978 August 14; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888574)
    - "Argast 2 - copy", undated; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888582)
    - "Copy of MAHA film #20", undated; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888590)
    - "Brook - Paris", May 22; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888608)
    - "Brook, Paris, side 3 and 4", May 22; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888616)
    - "Brook - copy, Maha film", undated; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888624)
    - "Peter Brook", 1979 December 21; 1 (Box 9, Item barcode 39002104888632)
    - "The last 1/2 hour, Paris (Hamlet)", 2000 December; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104886974)
    - "Brook Press Conference", 1971 August 31; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104886982)
    - "Brook Maha Film 2", undated; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887030)
    - "Grotowski and Brook meeting, Wroclaw Symposium", 1975 June [15?]; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887006)
    - "Jean Claude Carrière, Avignon", 1985; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887014)
    - "Margaret Croyden and Peter Brook", 2004 December; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887022)
    - "Peter Brook - Margaret Croyden (moderator Glenn Loney)", 1987 November 10; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104886990)
    - "Brook Wife", 1979 December 21; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887048)
    - "Filed under Personal, transcribed; B is first then A: Maha", [1987?]; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887055)
    - "Peter Brook film; meeting with / 'Sacred Dances'", copy and original, 1977 July 19; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887063)
    - "Peter Brook continued (end of tape: Pelleas) II", 1993 April 1; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887071)
    - "[Peter] Brook - Carmen ", 1983; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887089)
    - "Peter Brook, 'Un Homme Qui', Paris, transcribed and printed out / Jean Claude", 1993 April 1; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887097)
    - "Peter Brook and Obolensky / Mahabharata", 1985; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887105)
    - "Brook, Yoshi, original and copy, #22, [1970?]; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887113)
    - "Brook and Yoshi, both sides, given for transcription, copy #22", [1970?]; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887121)
    - "Jon Jory", undated; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887139)
    - "Brook II - Avignon, Mahabharata", 1985; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887147)
    - "David Grossman", 1994; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887154)
    - "Brook - Tempest, edited, side 2", undated; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887162)
    - "Joe Melillo", undated; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887170)
    - "Tony Randall and side one, Yossi Yisraeli[?], undated; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887188)
    - "Brook, Carmen / Elan", 1983; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887196)
    - "Peter Brook, Hamlet, Paris, 2000 December 14; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887204)
    - "Peter Brook 3, London - Gurd[?] film", 1977; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887212)
    - "Brook tape I, starts in middle / Alan Bates", undated; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887220)
    - "Brook - my[?] Maha", undated; 1 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002104887238)
  - Slides, undated; 7 (Box 11)
  - Photographs and postcards, 1998, undated; 6 (Box 11)
  - Computer media
    - Tempest2 Tempest 93 piece Taromena Pelle as Sacks 93 Interview 93 Pilleas 2 Proposal Project (2000) see attached sheet for more [More] Brook Original Files of C:\Brook: includ finished MSS, 2005-ycal-1110-c-0001; 1 (Box 12)
      Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - PETER BROOK INTERVIEW, 2005-ycal-1110-c-0002; 1 (Box 12)
    - Brook manuscript 2002, 2005-ycal-1110-c-0003; 1 (Box 12)
    - "Conversations With Peter Brook" complete MSS. File: B:\** (doesn't come up), 2005-ycal-1110-c-0004; 1 (Box 12)
    - 43741 AIT 22058 Farrar, Straus "Conversations with Peter Brook" fig #1 replacement, 2005-ycal-1110-c-0005; 1 (Box 12)
- 2011 Addition to November 2005 Acquisition, 1965-2011; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  The 2011 Addition contains material acquired by the library from Croyden in 2011.
  - "Copy Edited Brook Mss," draft, typescript, corrected, 2002 (Box 13)
  - "Dangerous Places, Dangerous Times: A Reporter's Notebooks: World War II - Cold War," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 13)
  - Loose material, 1987-2011; 3 (Box 14)
  - The PEN Newsletter, 1995-1997 (Box 14)
  - "Gypsy", 2008 (Box 14)
  - "Off Broadway", 1965-1989, undated (Box 14)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 14)
  - "Extra Copies Unedited Reporter's Notebook", undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous writings, 1973-2007 (Box 15)
  - "A Reporter's Notebook," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15)
  - "Reviews Orghast Peter Brook 1971", 1971, undated (Box 15)
  - "Grotowski", 1999; 2 (Box 15)
  - Material relating to La Mama, undated (Box 15)
  - Notebooks, 1977; 2 (Box 15)
  - Notebooks, 1991, undated (Box 16)
  - Printed material, undated; 3 (Box 16)
  - "Peter Brook on Charlie Rose", 2001; YCALMSS577_0023; 1; 02:00:28 (Box 38)
    Restricted fragile material.
  - "'Jerzy Grotowski: 1973', Creative Arts Television, Kent CT", YCALMSS577_0024; 1; 00:30:01; PAL (Box 39)
    There is a write-up on Jerzy Grotowski on the back of the tape. It reads: Jerzy Growtowski: 1973 In this episode of "Conversations About Theater" Jerzy Grotowski speaks with Margaret Croyden, well known American theater critic and author of "Lunatics, Lovers and Poets: The Contemporary Experimental Theater". His translator is Jacques Chwat. This interview was recorded in 1973. Grotowski had recenty returned from several months of vagabonding around the United States. He discusses his personal changes and new persepectives for his Polish Laboratory Theater. Copyright: 2006, Creative Arts Television
  - "Mother" (audiotape reel), 1974; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002104886958)
    Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Computer media
    - Tempest PB 3 leaning PB closeup PB2 siting Hamlet Hamlet 2 far shot, 2005-ycal-1110-c-0006; 1 (Box 17)
    - PB black sweater Hamlet Andrew w/ stall, 2005-ycal-1110-c-0007; 1 (Box 17)
- December 2015 Acquistion, 1922-2013; 11.18 linear feet (18 boxes) + 1 broadside
  This series is arranged in loose groupings by format as received by the library.
  The December 2015 Addition documents the personal and professional life of Margaret Croyden. Typed and photocopied drafts of Croyden's manuscripts "Farewell Mr. Hemingway", "The Years in Between: A Reporter's Journey", and other works are included in the addition, as is her correspondence wtih literary agents and publishers. Press files concerning the publication of her books "In the Shadow of the Flame," "Conversations with Peter Brook (1970- 2000)," and "The Years In Between: A Reporter's Journey" are also included. The addition also contains copies of her column "Croyden's Corner", her reviews in the New York Theater Wire, and other publications; Croyden's notes as a student and a teacher; and notes from her travels.
  - Writings and Publications, 1975-2011; Series I; 1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
    Series I includes manuscript drafts of Croyden's works; correspondence with literary agents and publishers; press release information for books; and book proposals.
    Series I is arranged in loose groupings by format as recieved by the library.
    - Remembering and Forgetting manuscript and publisher correspondence, 1975–1984 (Box 18)
    - The Center printed pamphlet and typescript, annotated, 1980; undated (Box 18)
    - Typescript fragments of unidentified works, corrected and annotated, 1982; undated (Box 18)
    - Proposal for Israeli story, typescript and typescript copies, annotated, 1985; undated (Box 18)
    - The Search for Spiritual Theater Collected Essays proposal, computer printout, 1988–1992; undated (Box 18)
    - In the Shadow of the Flame correspondence and publication documents, 1993–2003 (Box 18)
    - It Snowed that Winter correspondence and notes, 1997 (Box 18)
    - The Years in Between